Did you lie to me?
هل كذبت علي؟
I didn't lie.
أنا لم أكذب.
So what was it?
إذن ماذا كان؟
It's just...
إنه فقط...
I was trying to find the right moment.
كنت أحاول العثور على اللحظة المناسبة.
Were you ever going to tell me
هل كنت ستقول لي من أي وقت مضى
or were you going to keep lying?
أم أنك ستستمر في الكذب؟
If I tried to hide it, I wouldn't have told you.
لو حاولت إخفاء ذلك، لم أكن لأخبرك.
So it wasn't the right time?
إذن لم يكن الوقت المناسب؟
I did not mean that.
لم أقصد ذلك
So what do you mean?
إذن ماذا تقصد؟
You say you don't have a son?
هل تقول أنه ليس لديك ابن؟
Did it seem that easy to you?
هل بدا الأمر بهذه السهولة بالنسبة لك؟
Did you think I was so alone
هل اعتقدت أنني كنت وحيدا جدا
I wouldn't mind if you had a child?
لا أمانع إذا كان لديك طفل؟
Anything else you want to confess?
هل هناك أي شيء آخر تريد الاعتراف به؟
Any criminal record?
أي سجل جنائي؟
I was afraid you would react like that...
كنت أخشى أن تكون ردة فعلك هكذا..
That's why it was difficult for me to tell you.
ولهذا السبب كان من الصعب علي أن أخبرك.
I was afraid...
كنت خائفا...
because I like you a lot.
لأنني أحبك كثيرا.
How do you think that makes me feel?
كيف تعتقد أن هذا يجعلني أشعر؟
I hate myself for loving you,
كرهت نفسي لأنني أحببتك
for trusting someone like you.
لثقتك بشخص مثلك.
I regret it a lot.
أنا نادم على ذلك كثيرا.
[Do Hyun]
[دو هيون]
I'll stop by this weekend to get my things.
سأتوقف في نهاية هذا الأسبوع للحصول على أغراضي.
If it makes you uncomfortable, I will come when you are not at home.
إذا كان ذلك يجعلك غير مرتاح، فسوف آتي عندما لا تكون في المنزل.
[Idiot]
[الأبله]
- Hello. - Where are you?
- مرحبًا. - أين أنت؟
- At home. - What are you doing?
- في المنزل. - ماذا تفعل؟
I have an existential crisis.
عندي أزمة وجودية.
Some create masterpieces at 18,
البعض يصنع روائع في سن 18،
and others
وغيرها
they are 27 and correct typographical errors of others.
هم 27 وتصحيح الأخطاء المطبعية للآخرين.
I'm going there.
انا ذاهب الى هناك.
I just showered and changed.
لقد استحممت للتو وغيرت ملابسي.
So what? Just wait for me.
فماذا؟ فقط انتظرني.
- Know? - That?
- يعرف؟ - الذي - التي؟
You don't usually try that hard in life.
أنت لا تحاول عادة هذا الجهد في الحياة.
Don't start, just read it.
لا تبدأ، فقط اقرأها.
Do graduate students Do they always write such long essays?
هل طلاب الدراسات العليا هل يكتبون دائمًا مثل هذه المقالات الطويلة؟
Is it too much?
هل هو أكثر من اللازم؟
There is a saying:
هناك قول مأثور:
"I didn't have time to write a short letter,
"لم يكن لدي الوقت لكتابة رسالة قصيرة،
so I wrote a long one."
لذلك كتبت واحدة طويلة."
It's by Mark Twain.
إنه لمارك توين.
See?
يرى؟
The longer it is,
كلما كانت أطول،
more it shows that you are not ready.
أكثر يدل على أنك غير مستعد.
So help me adjust it,
لذا ساعدوني في تعديله
to make it precise and irrefutable.
لجعلها دقيقة ولا يمكن دحضها.
let me benefit of the future great writer.
اسمحوا لي أن أستفيد للكاتب العظيم في المستقبل.
Good.
جيد.
That smells amazing.
تلك الرائحة مذهلة.
It's crazy.
إنه جنون.
It's delicious, right?
إنه لذيذ، أليس كذلك؟
My parents returned to the field for their garden,
عاد والداي إلى الحقل من أجل حديقتهما،
so I basically lived in your house and I ate all your food.
لذلك عشت في منزلك بشكل أساسي وأكلت كل طعامك.
Yes, I told you to move.
نعم، قلت لك أن تتحرك.
Clear.
واضح.
Your mom's kimchi fried rice was the best.
أرز الكيمتشي المقلي الخاص بوالدتك كان الأفضل.
Hey,
مهلا،
what's wrong with you?
ما خطبك؟
I just miss your mom.
أنا فقط أفتقد والدتك.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
Still, it feels good,
ومع ذلك، فإنه يشعر بالارتياح،
because I can talk about my mother.
لأنني أستطيع أن أتحدث عن والدتي.
If I had known that he would leave so suddenly,
لو كنت أعلم أنه سيغادر فجأةً،
I would have tried harder
كنت سأحاول بجهد أكبر
to become someone sooner.
لتصبح شخصا عاجلا.
It's a real shame.
إنه عار حقيقي.
[Listen 25 Minimarket]
[استمع 25 ميني ماركت]
It seems the power went out.
يبدو أن الطاقة انقطعت.
Do you have cash?
هل لديك نقود؟
No.
لا.
I don't have cash either.
ليس لدي نقود أيضاً.
I'll return this and leave.
سأعيد هذا وأغادر.
No, I'll take care of it.
لا، سأعتني بالأمر.
Why is there no light?
لماذا لا يوجد ضوء؟
Why is it so dark here?
لماذا هو مظلم جدا هنا؟
Give me a pack of cigarettes.
أعطني علبة سجائر.
Sorry, the power went out.
آسف، لقد انقطعت الكهرباء.
Do you have cash?
هل لديك نقود؟
Who carries cash nowadays?
من يحمل النقود هذه الأيام؟
The box doesn't work, so the cards are useless.
الصندوق لا يعمل، لذا فإن البطاقات عديمة الفائدة.
Now you disrespect me?
الآن أنت لا تحترمني؟
Do you look down on me?
هل تنظر إليّ باستخفاف؟
What are you taking about?
ما الذي تتناوله؟
He said the cards don't work because of the blackout.
وقال البطاقات لا تعمل بسبب انقطاع التيار الكهربائي.
Who the hell are you?
من أنت بحق الجحيم؟
-And who the hell are you? - That?
-ومن أنت بحق الجحيم؟ - الذي - التي؟
How dare they?
كيف يجرؤون؟
You two...
أنتما...
Give me the cigarettes now!
أعطني السجائر الآن!
Yes sir.
نعم يا سيدي.
What are you looking at?
ما الذي تنظر إليه؟
Police? I'm in a store in the Yeonhwa neighborhood.
شرطة؟ أنا في متجر في حي يونهوا.
There's a drunk here.
هناك في حالة سكر هنا.
He throws things and threatens us.
يرمي الأشياء ويهددنا.
Please come immediately.
يرجى الحضور على الفور.
It seems that the entire area is in darkness.
ويبدو أن المنطقة بأكملها في الظلام.
My boss told us to close until the light came back.
أخبرنا مديري أن نغلق حتى عاد النور.
I can't serve customers,
لا أستطيع خدمة العملاء،
just in case that things get out of control.
فقط في حالة أن تخرج الأمور عن السيطرة.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
You can close the door.
يمكنك إغلاق الباب.
Do you want me to stay with you?
هل تريد مني أن أبقى معك؟
If I go home, it will be dark too,
إذا عدت إلى المنزل، سيكون الظلام أيضًا،
and I don't even have candles.
وليس لدي حتى الشموع.
Those who listen to "Night Walk" They have known it for a while:
أولئك الذين يستمعون إلى "Night Walk" لقد عرفوا ذلك منذ فترة:
I love cherry blossoms.
أنا أحب أزهار الكرز.
You hear this, right?
تسمع هذا، أليس كذلك؟
Spring It came especially late this year.
الربيع لقد جاء متأخرًا بشكل خاص هذا العام.
I heard that the flowers would open late too,
سمعت أن الزهور ستتفتح متأخرًا أيضًا
so I waited and waited
لذلك انتظرت وانتظرت
in the hope of seeing them in full bloom,
على أمل رؤيتها في كامل إزهارها،
but a sudden rain He made them fall before their time.
ولكن المطر المفاجئ لقد جعلهم يسقطون قبل أوانهم.
In the end, I missed them.
في النهاية، اشتقت إليهم.
Why do good things Do they disappear so quickly?
لماذا تفعل الأشياء الجيدة هل يختفون بهذه السرعة؟
How did he hide that he had a son?
وكيف أخفى أن له ولدا؟
One becomes two, and suddenly there are variables.
واحد يصبح اثنين، وفجأة هناك متغيرات.
No, actually there are three.
لا، في الواقع هناك ثلاثة.
Do you find it funny?
هل تجد ذلك مضحكا؟
At least he's not married.
على الأقل هو غير متزوج.
And if he stays alone at Jun Kyung's house,
وإذا بقي بمفرده في منزل جون كيونغ،
You are not raising your child.
أنت لا تربي طفلك.
What is the problem?
ما هي المشكلة؟
He's divorced, right?
إنه مطلق، أليس كذلك؟
- How old is the child? - Enough.
- كم عمر الطفل؟ - كافٍ.
What does that matter now?
ما أهمية ذلك الآن؟
Anyway, delete his number.
على كل حال، احذف رقمه.
If you save it, you will wait for me to call you
إذا قمت بحفظه، سوف تنتظر مني أن أتصل بك
and you will end up calling him when you feel alone.
وسوف ينتهي بك الأمر بالاتصال به عندما تشعر بالوحدة.
I already deleted it.
لقد حذفته بالفعل.
You probably memorized it.
ربما حفظت ذلك.
Erase it from your head too.
امسحها من رأسك أيضًا.
You need a drink.
أنت بحاجة إلى مشروب.
Drink and forget everything.
اشرب وانسى كل شيء.
Let's drink.
دعونا نشرب.
Are you really going to break up with him?
هل حقا سوف تنفصلين عنه؟
In fact, we're done.
في الواقع، لقد انتهينا.
Didn't you hear he has a son?
ألم تسمع أن لديه ولد؟
What better reason to break up?
ما هو أفضل سبب للانفصال؟
Let's go...
دعنا نذهب...
It's like you always wait a reason to leave.
يبدو الأمر كما لو كنت تنتظر دائمًا سببا للمغادرة.
Did you hear his version?
هل سمعت نسخته؟
The reason I didn't tell you?
السبب الذي لم أخبرك به؟
Hey, you still love him, right?
مهلا، أنت لا تزال تحبه، أليس كذلك؟
Isn't that a very strong reason to continue?
أليس هذا سببا قويا جدا للاستمرار؟
- Who is it? - Hey,
- من هذا؟ - مهلا،
don't answer
لا تجيب
It's not Do Hyun.
إنه ليس دو هيون.
You don't need to remember the number of a scammer.
لا تحتاج إلى أن تتذكر عدد المحتال.
Hello?
مرحبًا؟
Yeah.
نعم.
At first,
في البداية،
this space asked for it a terminally ill father.
طلبت هذه المساحة ذلك أب مريض بمرض عضال.
His family paid a deposit for months
دفعت عائلته وديعة لعدة أشهر
to reserve it specifically.
لحجزها على وجه التحديد.
There was an error on the part of our staff.
لقد حدث خطأ من جانب موظفينا.
We sincerely apologize.
نحن نعتذر بصدق.
How could something like this happen?
كيف يمكن أن يحدث شيء مثل هذا؟
I don't understand.
لا أفهم.
We were surprised too when we found out.
لقد فوجئنا أيضًا عندما اكتشفنا ذلك.
Were you surprised?
هل تفاجأت؟
Do you think this is like canceling a reservation at a restaurant?
هل تعتقد أن هذا مثل الإلغاء حجز في مطعم؟
We have nothing more to say.
ليس لدينا المزيد لنقوله.
That's all?
هذا كل شيء؟
Once again, We offer you our most sincere apologies.
مرة أخرى، نحن نقدم لك اعتذاراتنا الصادقة.
Do you think an apology will fix this?
هل تعتقد أن الاعتذار سيصلح هذا؟
So is there any space left?
فهل هناك أي مساحة متبقية؟
Yes. Please follow me.
نعم. من فضلك اتبعني.
Here.
هنا.
Thank you all for this great day.
شكرا لكم جميعا على هذا اليوم العظيم.
Yes, thanks!
نعم شكرا!
We will return to our hotels and rest,
سنعود إلى فنادقنا ونستريح
and then we'll see each other tonight dressed in our best clothes.
وبعد ذلك سنرى بعضنا البعض الليلة نرتدي أفضل ملابسنا.
- OK. - See you.
- نعم. - أرك لاحقًا.
- See you tonight. - Thank you.
- أراك الليلة. - شكرًا لك.
Let them rest.
دعهم يستريحون.
Jun Kyung, how are you?
جون كيونغ، كيف حالك؟
Good.
جيد.
How are you, dad?
كيف حالك يا أبي؟
It's nice here.
إنه لطيف هنا.
Good weather, breeze, sea.
الطقس الجيد والنسيم والبحر.
And you?
وأنت؟
Now I'm at home with Jun Seo.
الآن أنا في المنزل مع جون سيو.
Yes?
نعم؟
That's very good.
هذا جيد جدًا.
So, are you going to have dinner together?
هل ستتناولان العشاء معًا؟
Wait, dad...
انتظر يا أبي...
Yes?
نعم؟
Wait a second.
انتظر ثانية.
- Dad? - Hello, Jun Seo.
- أب؟ - مرحبا، جون سيو.
I felt bad for leaving without seeing you,
شعرت بالسوء لأنني غادرت دون رؤيتك،
but hearing your voice like that makes me feel better.
لكن سماع صوتك بهذه الطريقة يجعلني أشعر بالتحسن.
- Dad. - Yes?
- أبي. - نعم؟
I'm sorry for what happened earlier.
أنا آسف لما حدث في وقت سابق.
Have a good time.
وقتا ممتعا.
We don't want to ruin your day, do we?
نحن لا نريد أن نفسد يومك، أليس كذلك؟
- Come on? - Yes.
- تعال؟ - نعم.
They call just to see how I am, even when nothing happens.
إنهم يتصلون فقط ليروا كيف حالي، حتى عندما لا يحدث شيء.
It is usually the parents those who worry like this.
عادة ما يكون الوالدان أولئك الذين يقلقون مثل هذا.
Now that they've grown up, They are the ones who care about me.
والآن بعد أن كبروا، إنهم هم الذين يهتمون بي.
Looks like your kids turned out okay.
يبدو أن أطفالك أصبحوا بخير.
Yeah.
نعم.
My daughter is an obstetrician and gynecologist,
ابنتي طبيبة نساء وتوليد
and my son is doing graduate school.
وابني يدرس في الدراسات العليا.
They are very friendly.
إنهم ودودون للغاية.
You must be proud.
يجب أن تكون فخورا.
But it's not that simple.
لكن الأمر ليس بهذه البساطة.
My son has not yet found what you love to do,
لم يتم العثور على ابني بعد ما تحب أن تفعله،
and that worries me.
وهذا يقلقني.
My daughter still hasn't found someone to love,
ابنتي لم تجد بعد من تحبه،
and that worries me too.
وهذا يقلقني أيضًا.
When did we take that photo?
متى التقطنا تلك الصورة؟
Was it the year you started college?
هل كان هذا هو العام الذي بدأت فيه الكلية؟
It was my orientation day.
لقد كان يوم توجيهي.
A few months before mom's accident.
قبل بضعة أشهر من حادث أمي.
We look very uncomfortable.
نحن نبدو غير مرتاحين للغاية.
Why were we smiling like that?
لماذا كنا نبتسم هكذا؟
You look...
أنت تبدو...
very good.
جيد جدًا.
Dear?
عزيزي؟
Know? In retrospect,
يعرف؟ في الماضي،
Our family was not so happy, Even before mom's accident,
عائلتنا لم تكن سعيدة للغاية، حتى قبل حادث أمي،
but we weren't unhappy either.
لكننا لم نكن سعداء أيضًا.
Do you think so?
هل تعتقد ذلك؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
We were normal.
كنا طبيعيين.
We...
نحن...
No, I...
لا، أنا...
I think I blamed mom for my unhappiness.
أعتقد أنني ألوم أمي على تعاستي.
It was my fault.
كانت غلطتي.
Gosh, the power went out again.
يا إلهي، انقطعت الكهرباء مرة أخرى.
- Hey. - Yeah?
- يا. - نعم؟
Do you think this has happened when mom was alone?
هل تعتقد أن هذا قد حدث عندما كانت أمي وحدها؟
He must have been scared.
لا بد أنه كان خائفًا.
Yes.
نعم.
She probably felt lonely too.
ربما شعرت بالوحدة أيضًا.
Honey,
عزيزي
why are you in the dark?
لماذا أنت في الظلام؟
I understand, the power went out.
أدركت أن التيار الكهربائي انقطع.
Ready.
جاهز.
Now there is light.
الآن هناك ضوء.
Next time the power goes out, go there...
في المرة القادمة التي تنقطع فيها الكهرباء، اذهب إلى هناك...
Honey.
العسل.
I'm sorry.
أنا آسف.
I shouldn't have said that, I'm sorry.
لم يكن من المفترض أن أقول ذلك، أنا آسف.
Don't cry.
لا تبكي.
You were afraid, right?
كنت خائفًا، أليس كذلك؟
I'm very sorry.
أنا آسف جدًا.
I'm sorry I came home late.
أنا آسف لأنني عدت إلى المنزل متأخرًا.
Honey, don't cry.
عزيزتي، لا تبكي.
It wasn't late.
لم يكن متأخرا.
I always had you
لقد كنت دائما معك
at my side
في جانبي
That's why I felt sorry
لهذا السبب شعرت بالأسف
and gratitude every day.
والامتنان كل يوم.
- Dear. - Don't cry,
- عزيزي. - لا تبكي،
everyone is waiting for you outside.
الجميع ينتظرك في الخارج.
you look
نظرتم
amazing today.
مذهل اليوم.
That?
الذي - التي؟
That woman, Ja Yeong,
تلك المرأة، جا يونغ،
It's pretty.
انها جميلة.
It looks good on you.
تبدو جيدة عليك.
Don't say that.
لا تقل ذلك.
Don't hesitate anymore, don't hold back.
لا تتردد بعد الآن، لا تبخل.
you should think
يجب أن تفكر
in you
فيك
and live for you.
ويعيش لك.
I want you to be truly happy.
أريدك أن تكون سعيدا حقا.
OK.
نعم.
Every day,
كل يوم،
be happy.
كن سعيدا.
Dear.
عزيزي.
Dear!
عزيزي!
- Sorry. - Yeah?
- آسف. - نعم؟
Is there a tall and thin man middle-aged inside?
هل يوجد رجل طويل ورفيع في منتصف العمر في الداخل؟
There is no one.
لا يوجد أحد.
Mr. Seo Jin Ho?
السيد سيو جين هو؟
Mr. Seo?
السيد سيو؟
What are you doing here?
ما الذي تفعله هنا؟
Did something happen?
هل حدث شيء ما؟
Maybe you don't understand
ربما أنت لا تفهم
why am I like this?
لماذا انا هكذا؟
I feel like I'm the only one who lives well...
أشعر وكأنني الوحيد الذي يعيش بشكل جيد..
and that makes me feel very guilty.
وهذا يجعلني أشعر بالذنب الشديد.
It hurts a lot.
إنه يؤلم كثيرا.
It would be stranger if you didn't feel that way.
سيكون الأمر غريبًا إذا لم تشعر بهذه الطريقة.
No.
لا.
You already got over it.
لقد تجاوزت الأمر بالفعل.
Someone weak like me,
من هو ضعيف مثلي
these feelings...
هذه المشاعر...
You wouldn't understand.
لن تفهم.
I understand you...
أنا أفهمك...
more than anyone.
أكثر من أي شخص.
My husband was always busy and distant.
كان زوجي دائمًا مشغولًا وبعيدًا.
When I felt sorry,
عندما شعرت بالأسف،
he promised me that,
لقد وعدني بذلك،
when he retired,
عندما تقاعد
we would travel together the pilgrimage path.
سوف نسافر معًا طريق الحج.
But he
لكنه
he could never keep that promise.
لا يمكنه الوفاء بهذا الوعد أبدًا.
I thought about it for a long time.
فكرت في الأمر لفترة طويلة.
"What would it mean to go alone?"
"ماذا يعني الذهاب بمفردك؟"
But in the end,
لكن في النهاية
I went alone,
لقد ذهبت وحدي
like you.
مثلك.
Do you know what I packed when I left?
هل تعرف ما الذي حزمته عندما غادرت؟
For the last day of the pilgrimage,
في اليوم الأخير من الحج،
for that day...
لذلك اليوم...
I went from hospital to hospital,
كنت أذهب من مستشفى إلى آخر،
gathering sleeping pills.
جمع الحبوب المنومة.
I emptied the jar,
لقد أفرغت الجرة
I lay down and lay motionless in bed.
استلقيت على السرير واستلقيت بلا حراك.
And, suddenly,
وفجأة
I felt very sorry for myself.
شعرت بالأسف الشديد على نفسي.
It wasn't that I wanted to live for my husband.
لم يكن الأمر أنني أردت أن أعيش من أجل زوجي.
I felt very pathetic...
شعرت بالشفقة الشديدة...
and my life was unbearably sad.
وكانت حياتي حزينة بشكل لا يطاق.
The life I still had left...
الحياة التي مازلت باقية لي...
I was too valuable to give up.
لقد كنت ذا قيمة كبيرة لدرجة أنني لا أستطيع الاستسلام.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
It must have been difficult to talk about.
لا بد أنه كان من الصعب الحديث عنه.
I just wanted to say
أردت فقط أن أقول
that your life is not over yet.
أن حياتك لم تنته بعد.
They say life is a festival.
يقولون أن الحياة مهرجان.
Our festival is not over yet.
مهرجاننا لم ينته بعد.
Do you want to go out?
هل تريد الخروج؟
For our latest song, we are accepting requests.
لأحدث أغنيتنا، نحن نقبل الطلبات.
If you have one...
إذا كان لديك واحدة...
How about a song What would your wife love?
ماذا عن أغنية ماذا ستحب زوجتك؟
No.
لا.
Let's ask for a song that you like.
دعونا نطلب الأغنية التي تحبها.
My name is Ja Yeong.
اسمي جا يونغ.
Jin Ja Yeong.
جين جا يونج.
Very good, Ja Yeong.
جيد جدًا، جا يونج.
Let's listen together to a song that you like.
دعونا نستمع معا إلى الأغنية التي تحبها.
Aren't we exaggerating?
ألسنا نبالغ؟
Come here to look for him?
تعال هنا للبحث عنه؟
We are not usually this type of family.
نحن لسنا عادة هذا النوع من الأسرة.
Dad must have felt very alone traveling without company.
لا بد أن أبي شعر بالوحدة الشديدة السفر بدون شركة.
Yes,
نعم،
It is probable.
فمن المحتمل.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
since when do you say the right thing?
منذ متى تقول الشيء الصحيح؟
Yes, well,
نعم، حسنا،
I guess your conscience is affecting you.
أعتقد أن ضميرك يؤثر عليك.
You were busy dating the guy next door, right?
كنت مشغولا مواعدة الرجل المجاور، أليس كذلك؟
How long has it been?
كم من الوقت مضى؟
That?
الذي - التي؟
I was waiting for an answer. Why so quiet?
كنت أنتظر الجواب. لماذا هذا الهدوء؟
The truth
الحقيقة
It's just that we don't treat each other well as a family.
الأمر فقط أننا لا نعامل بعضنا البعض بشكل جيد كعائلة.
Let's try it.
دعونا نحاول ذلك.
Silently, so that no one notices.
بصمت، حتى لا يلاحظ أحد.
Look, there's dad.
انظر، هناك أبي.
Don't make a funny face, do it for him.
لا تصنعي وجهًا مضحكًا، افعلي ذلك من أجله.
Worry about yourself.
تقلق على نفسك.
Everyone in our group They had strong personalities.
الجميع في مجموعتنا كان لديهم شخصيات قوية.
Thanks to you,
شكرا لك،
I had a great time.
لقد قضيت وقتا رائعا.
Me too.
أنا أيضاً.
This journey will accompany me for a long time.
هذه الرحلة سوف ترافقني لفترة طويلة.
- Dad! - Over here!
- أب! - هنا!
It looks good, doesn't it?
تبدو جيدة، أليس كذلك؟
He's probably holding on.
ربما هو متمسك.
Say hello well.
قل مرحبا جيدا.
Mr. Seo,
السيد سيو،
It's time to wake up from oblivion.
حان وقت الاستيقاظ من النسيان.
[Information document about burial in trees]
[وثيقة معلومات عن الدفن في الأشجار]
They say that even the urn will decompose there.
يقولون أنه حتى الجرة سوف تتحلل هناك.
Everything returns to earth.
كل شيء يعود إلى الأرض.
Isn't that a little strange?
أليس هذا غريبا بعض الشيء؟
What do you think, dad?
ما رأيك يا أبي؟
You haven't eaten yet, have you?
أنت لم تأكل بعد، أليس كذلك؟
Is something wrong?
هل هناك خطأ ما؟
No.
لا.
I know it may sound strange, but...
أعلم أن الأمر قد يبدو غريبًا، لكن...
mom passed away,
توفيت أمي،
and you ask if something happens?
وتسأل إذا حدث شيء؟
Isn't that a little strange?
أليس هذا غريبا بعض الشيء؟
How about
ماذا عن
something spicy?
شيء حار؟
Like what?
مثل ماذا؟
Whatever they want.
كل ما يريدون.
So,
لذا،
How about tteokbokki?
ماذا عن tteokbokki؟
Isn't it very spicy?
أليس حار جدا؟
You ask for it.
أنت تطلب ذلك.
I don't have my phone now. Can you order?
ليس لدي هاتفي الآن. هل يمكنك الطلب؟
[Julia, Kim Mi Ran]
[جوليا، كيم مي ران]
Well done, Jun Kyung.
أحسنت، جون كيونغ.
your mom
والدتك
I was stuck at home all the time.
لقد كنت عالقا في المنزل طوال الوقت.
This open place suits you better.
هذا المكان المفتوح يناسبك بشكل أفضل.
My sister has a tree now.
أختي لديها شجرة الآن.
My dear, I may not come often,
عزيزتي، ربما لا آتي كثيرًا،
but I will visit you when I can.
ولكن سأزورك عندما أستطيع.
Take care of yourself.
اعتنِ بنفسك.
- That's better. - Yes.
- هذا أفضل. - نعم.
- It's cute.
- إنه لطيف.
I feel really bad for his dad.
أشعر بالسوء حقًا تجاه والده.
I couldn't live without her.
لم أستطع العيش بدونها.
What if he does something reckless?
ماذا لو فعل شيئًا متهورًا؟
Not only the dead deserve compassion.
ليس الموتى وحدهم يستحقون الرحمة.
The living too.
الأحياء أيضاً.
Take good care of your dad.
اعتني بوالدك جيدًا.
Take care of yourself
اعتني بنفسك
and stop getting drunk for no reason.
والتوقف عن السكر بدون سبب.
- Come on. -Have a drink with Jin Ho too.
- تعال. -تناول مشروبًا مع جين هو أيضًا.
I will do that.
سأفعل ذلك.
Don't forget the party tonight at six.
لا تنسَ الحفلة الليلة في الساعة السادسة.
Hello.
مرحبا.
"Popularize Korean legends with AI"?
"تعميم الأساطير الكورية باستخدام الذكاء الاصطناعي"؟
It sounds boring.
يبدو مملا.
Do you want to hear something funny?
هل تريد سماع شيء مضحك؟
You know Yuna, right?
أنت تعرف يونا، أليس كذلك؟
I'll do the choreography for your new song.
سأقوم بتصميم الرقصات لأغنيتك الجديدة.
Oh really?
أوه حقًا؟
What if I become too famous?
ماذا لو أصبحت مشهوراً جداً؟
Yes.
نعم.
- You're annoying. - What are you doing?
- أنت مزعج. - ماذا تفعل؟
TRUE.
حقيقي.
Whose choreography was it?
من كان تصميم الرقصات؟
It suits you perfectly.
إنه يناسبك تمامًا.
Yeah? Seem to you?
نعم؟ يبدو لك؟
It's a bit flashy.
انها براقة قليلا.
You are my boyfriend. How would it not work?
أنت صديقي. كيف لا يعمل؟
It's a lot of pressure.
إنه ضغط كبير.
I'm about to be even more famous,
أنا على وشك أن أصبح أكثر شهرة،
You better prepare for that.
من الأفضل أن تستعد لذلك.
Aren't you sick of plaid shirts?
لا أنت مريض من القمصان منقوشة؟
Hey, isn't that Yoon Sol?
مهلا، أليس هذا يون سول؟
I think so.
أعتقد ذلك.
It just can't be.
لا يمكن أن يكون الأمر كذلك.
It's me, come.
إنه أنا، تعال.
I follow you on Instagram,
انا اتابعك على الانستقرام ,
but you didn't follow me.
لكنك لم تتبعني.
I will do it if you send me a message.
سأفعل ذلك إذا أرسلت لي رسالة.
Can we take a photo with you?
هل يمكننا التقاط صورة معك؟
- Clear. - Thank you.
- واضح. - شكرًا لك.
- It's very good. - Delicious.
- انها جيدة جدا. - لذيذ.
It's tasty, right?
إنه لذيذ، أليس كذلك؟
Hey,
مهلا،
stop roasting and eat a little.
توقف عن التحميص وتناول القليل.
I'm eating.
أنا آكل.
You look better than you did a few days ago.
تبدو أفضل مما كنت عليه قبل بضعة أيام.
Yes, you must be eating well.
نعم، يجب أن تأكل جيدًا.
Eating well?
تناول الطعام بشكل جيد؟
No, it's because he doesn't have an annoying wife.
لا، لأنه ليس لديه زوجة مزعجة.
There you are.
ها أنت ذا.
- Our guide arrived. - Hello!
- وصل دليلنا. - مرحبًا!
How good to see you.
كم هو جيد أن أراك.
You're late, right?
لقد تأخرت، أليس كذلك؟
I'm late on purpose when I'm free.
لقد تأخرت عمدا عندما أكون متفرغا.
I'm tired of arriving early and take care of everything.
لقد سئمت من الوصول مبكرًا ورعاية كل شيء.
It seems like an eternity passed.
يبدو أن الأبدية مرت.
How good to see you all.
كم هو جيد أن أراكم جميعا.
Very well, eat.
جيد جداً، تناول الطعام.
- Let's toast. - Clear.
- دعونا نخب. - واضح.
Health!
صحة!
The marriage you lose will pay for the game, okay?
الزواج الذي تخسره سوف ندفع ثمن اللعبة، حسنا؟
- Sounds good. - Wait,
- ًيبدو جيدا. - انتظر،
They're not even married.
إنهم ليسوا متزوجين حتى.
So what are they?
إذن ما هم؟
- Losing team pays! - Deal done.
- خسارة الفريق تدفع! - تمت الصفقة.
I haven't played in 20 years.
لم ألعب منذ 20 عامًا.
Me neither. It's been more than ten years for me.
وأنا كذلك. لقد مرت أكثر من عشر سنوات بالنسبة لي.
Wow,
واو،
It looks like we'll pay for everything.
يبدو أننا سندفع ثمن كل شيء.
Let's do the best we can.
دعونا نبذل قصارى جهدنا.
- Everything went well, right? - Yes.
- كل شيء سار على ما يرام، أليس كذلك؟ - نعم.
Here it comes.
هنا يأتي.
Thank you, doctor.
شكرا لك يا دكتور.
Both mother and baby are healthy.
كل من الأم والطفل بصحة جيدة.
- Thank you. - Thank you so much.
- شكرًا لك. - شكراً جزيلاً.
- We appreciate it very much.
- نحن نقدر ذلك كثيرا.
Why did you do that?
لماذا فعلت ذلك؟
- You should have told him before. - I was going to do it,
- كان يجب أن تخبريه من قبل. - كنت سأفعل ذلك،
but you know.
لكنك تعلم.
I
أنا
and Jun Kyung...
و جون كيونغ...
We only met a couple of times.
التقينا مرتين فقط.
In the store...
في المتجر...
when I gave him a ride...
عندما أوصلته..
If I had told him: "I have a son..."
لو قلت له: "لدي ابن ..."
I couldn't do that.
لم أستطع أن أفعل ذلك.
And then we started dating...
ومن ثم بدأنا بالمواعدة..
and I didn't know
ولم أكن أعرف
When to tell the truth.
متى تقول الحقيقة.
I know it all seems like an excuse, but...
أعلم أن كل هذا يبدو كعذر، لكن...
Yes, I understand.
نعم، أنا أفهم.
When he said we should go slow,
عندما قال أننا يجب أن نسير ببطء،
I thought, "Okay,
فكرت: "حسنًا،
I will wait for the right moment."
سأنتظر اللحظة المناسبة."
That's what I repeated to myself.
وهذا ما كررته لنفسي.
Hey,
مهلا،
you liked him a lot.
كنت أحبه كثيرا.
So,
لذا،
Why don't you contact her again?
لماذا لا تتصل بها مرة أخرى؟
We're done.
لقد انتهينا.
Tell me.
أخبرني.
Let's hear your excuse.
دعونا نسمع عذرك.
At that moment,
في تلك اللحظة،
I realized.
أدركت.
I like it a lot more than I thought.
يعجبني هذا أكثر بكثير مما كنت أعتقد.
I am very sure of that.
أنا متأكد جدًا من ذلك.
That's why I need to see it again.
لهذا السبب أريد رؤيته مرة أخرى.
When I was 20,
عندما كان عمري 20 عامًا،
It was very...
لقد كان جداً...
immature
غير ناضج
Well...
حسنا...
I still am a little.
ما زلت قليلا.
My ex-girlfriend called me...
صديقتي السابقة اتصلت بي...
Two months after we broke up.
بعد شهرين من انفصالنا.
She said she was pregnant.
قالت إنها حامل.
Suddenly...
فجأة...
the idea of having a child...
فكرة إنجاب طفل..
honestly...
بصراحة...
It scared me.
لقد أخافني.
As for
أما بالنسبة
I saw his face...
رأيت وجهه..
I felt overwhelmed...
شعرت بالإرهاق...
and moved.
وانتقلت.
I was...
كنت...
strangely moved.
انتقل بشكل غريب.
That's how I felt.
هكذا شعرت.
but
لكن
we were already done,
لقد انتهينا بالفعل،
and try to return
ومحاولة العودة
just for responsibility...
فقط من أجل المسؤولية..
It wasn't possible.
لم يكن ذلك ممكنا.
My ex took the baby and went to Germany to study.
زوجي السابق أخذ الطفل وذهب إلى ألمانيا للدراسة.
We contacted again
اتصلنا مرة أخرى
last year.
العام الماضي.
my son
ابني
He wanted to meet me.
أراد مقابلتي.
I wanted to live in Korea.
أردت أن أعيش في كوريا.
So...
لذا...
after 14 years,
بعد 14 عاماً،
I met him.
التقيت به.
What's it called?
ماذا يطلق عليه؟
Daniel.
دانيال.
Im Daniel.
أنا دانيال.
He is 15
هو 15
and it is very tall.
وهو طويل جدًا.
He's in that cynical teenage phase, right?
إنه في مرحلة المراهقة الساخرة، أليس كذلك؟
Yes,
نعم،
Exactly.
بالضبط.
That little boy...
ذلك الولد الصغير...
while growing up...
بينما يكبر...
I couldn't do anything for him.
لم أستطع أن أفعل أي شيء له.
That is.
إنه.
That's my excuse.
هذا هو عذري.
What I really wanted to tell you...
ما أردت حقا أن أقوله لك...
no excuses...
لا أعذار...
is that...
هل هذا...
I'm very sorry.
أنا آسف جدا.
I've already forgiven you.
لقد سامحتك بالفعل.
From the moment I saw your face a while ago
منذ اللحظة التي رأيت فيها وجهك منذ فترة
I have something I want to give you.
لدي شيء أريد أن أقدمه لك.
Wait, you had this?
انتظر، هل كان لديك هذا؟
If we hadn't finished,
لو أننا لم ننتهي،
you would still listen to music one-sided forever.
ستظل تستمع إلى الموسيقى من جانب واحد إلى الأبد.
Thanks to you, We didn't have to pay for the game,
شكرا لك، لم يكن علينا أن ندفع ثمن اللعبة،
But I feel bad for the others.
لكني أشعر بالسوء تجاه الآخرين.
You don't seem that sorry. You tried so hard.
لا يبدو أنك آسف. لقد حاولت جاهدا.
I'm not usually competitive.
أنا لست عادة قادرة على المنافسة.
but tonight I didn't want to lose.
لكن الليلة لم أكن أريد أن أخسر.
Oh really? Because?
أوه حقًا؟ لأن؟
I don't mind losing alone, but you would have lost too.
لا أمانع أن أخسر وحدي، لكنك كنت ستخسر أيضًا.
- You're very kind. - No, come on.
- أنت طيب جدا. - لا، هيا.
I'm serious.
أنا جادة.
You are tall for your age,
أنت طويل بالنسبة لعمرك،
You don't have a belly or anything.
ليس لديك بطن أو أي شيء.
I'm holding her back right now.
أنا أحملها مرة أخرى الآن.
If you dyed your gray hair a little...
إذا صبغت شعرك الرمادي قليلاً..
Maybe you would look younger than me.
ربما ستبدو أصغر مني.
You said it was ten years ago that you didn't play bowling.
قلت أنه كان قبل عشر سنوات أنك لم تلعب البولينج.
How come you played so well?
كيف لعبت بشكل جيد؟
I try hard not to forget, that's all.
أحاول جاهدة ألا أنسى، هذا كل شيء.
When things are difficult, I try to forget,
عندما تكون الأمور صعبة، أحاول أن أنسى،
and when things are good,
وعندما تكون الأمور جيدة،
I try not to do it.
أحاول ألا أفعل ذلك.
Does that work when you want it to?
هل هذا يعمل عندما تريد ذلك؟
Are you curious?
هل أنت فضولي؟
Is this okay?
هل هذا جيد؟
What thing?
ما الشيء؟
Let him come like this to see a woman who lives alone.
دعه يأتي هكذا ليرى امرأة تعيش بمفردها.
you will not have
لن يكون لديك
Weird ideas, right?
أفكار غريبة، أليس كذلك؟
That?
الذي - التي؟
No, don't get me wrong.
لا، لا تفهموني خطأ.
I got scared.
لقد شعرت بالخوف.
This is Bom.
هذا بوم.
Hello.
مرحبًا.
- I didn't scare her, did I? - Not at all.
- أنا لم أخيفها، أليس كذلك؟ - مُطْلَقاً.
Did you have fun today? Greet him.
هل استمتعت اليوم؟ أحييه.
This place used to be a pool hall.
كان هذا المكان عبارة عن قاعة بلياردو.
With my work and my personality, I move a lot.
من خلال عملي وشخصيتي أتحرك كثيرا.
I never needed a place that felt like my home.
لم أكن بحاجة إلى مكان أبدا شعرت وكأنني بيتي.
A little unusual, isn't it?
غير عادية بعض الشيء، أليس كذلك؟
No,
لا،
I think it's wonderful.
أعتقد أنه رائع.
It feels
إنه يشعر
like a hiding place.
مثل مكان للاختباء.
You are a person...
أنت شخص...
incredible.
رائع.
Some buy souvenirs,
والبعض يشتري هدايا تذكارية
take photos
التقاط الصور
and publish them on social networks,
ونشرها على شبكات التواصل الاجتماعي،
but me
لكن أنا
just drawing.
مجرد رسم.
I draw the things I want to remember,
أرسم الأشياء التي أريد أن أتذكرها،
the things that I felt,
الأشياء التي شعرت بها،
the people I met and the conversations we had,
الناس الذين التقيت بهم والأحاديث التي دارت بيننا
so as not to forget them.
حتى لا ننساهم.
That's how I remember things.
هكذا أتذكر الأشياء.
What do you want to remember now?
ماذا تريد أن تتذكر الآن؟
Can I see it?
هل يمكنني رؤيته؟
- Yeah. - Gracias.
- نعم. - شكرا.
Vaya.
فايا.
He still has a lot to go.
لا يزال أمامه الكثير ليقطعه.
Are you really Seo Jun Seo?
هل أنت حقا سيو جون سيو؟
- That? - What's that?
- الذي - التي؟ - ما هذا؟
Are they punishing you or something?
هل يعاقبونك أم ماذا؟
- It doesn't suit me, does it? - No not at all.
- لا يناسبني، أليس كذلك؟ - لا إطلاقاً.
Sol bought it for me.
اشتراها لي سول.
It doesn't suit you.
انها لا تناسبك.
I thought so too.
اعتقدت ذلك أيضا.
Why do they go out if they don't even match?
لماذا يخرجون إذا لم يكونوا متطابقين حتى؟
Because I like it.
لأنني أحب ذلك.
Because she's pretty, right?
لأنها جميلة، أليس كذلك؟
Well,
حسنا،
It's great.
إنه أمر رائع.
He knows what he wants.
فهو يعرف ما يريد.
It does everything well.
يفعل كل شيء بشكل جيد.
Why would you like me,
لماذا تريدني،
a loser?
خاسر؟
Why are you a loser?
لماذا أنت خاسر؟
You're great too.
أنت عظيم أيضا.
Oh really?
أوه حقًا؟
In what sense?
بأي معنى؟
She's always busy,
إنها مشغولة دائمًا،
It always makes you nervous.
يجعلك دائما عصبيا.
It is very thin, I don't even think she's that pretty,
إنها رقيقة جدًا، أنا لا أعتقد حتى أنها جميلة إلى هذا الحد،
but you are always on his side.
ولكنك دائما إلى جانبه.
Yeah, that's what makes you a cool guy.
نعم، هذا ما يجعلك رجلاً رائعاً.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
What does it matter if you think I'm cool?
ماذا يهم إذا كنت تعتقد أنني رائع؟
Sol is the one who should think that.
سول هو من يجب أن يعتقد ذلك.
Why can't it be me?
لماذا لا يمكن أن يكون أنا؟
Let's stop.
دعونا نتوقف.
See you later.
أراك لاحقًا.
Dad?
أب؟
A grandmother from my sister's town raised Bom.
قامت جدة من بلدة أختي بتربية بوم.
He passed away, and Bom was left alone.
لقد مات، وبقي بوم وحده.
That's horrible.
هذا فظيع.
I felt alone, so I took her in,
لقد شعرت بالوحدة، لذا أخذتها،
but more time passes in the nursery than with me.
ولكن المزيد من الوقت يمر في الحضانة من معي.
I tell myself I'm busy,
أقول لنفسي أنا مشغول
and I think that makes her feel alone.
وأعتقد أن هذا يجعلها تشعر بالوحدة.
Is the man in the drawing your husband?
هل الرجل الذي في الرسمة هو زوجك؟
Never!
أبداً!
No? What a relief.
لا؟ يا لها من راحة.
It was part of a couples tour
لقد كان جزءًا من جولة للأزواج
and he wouldn't stop flirting with me.
ولن يتوقف عن مغازلتي.
His wife was there. What was I thinking?
وكانت زوجته هناك. ماذا كنت أفكر؟
It was a cruise ship, so there was no escape.
لقد كانت سفينة سياحية، لذلك لم يكن هناك مفر.
It was very uncomfortable and annoying.
كان الأمر غير مريح ومزعج للغاية.
I drew him to curse him for life.
لقد جذبته لألعنه مدى الحياة.
That?
الذي - التي؟
That guy is an idiot.
هذا الرجل هو احمق.
Married and disgusting, seriously.
متزوج ومثير للاشمئزاز، على محمل الجد.
Do you curse too?
هل تلعن أيضا؟
Anyone with common sense would do it.
أي شخص لديه الحس السليم سيفعل ذلك.
He's a damn.
انه لعنة.
- You can answer. - OK.
- يمكنك الإجابة. - نعم.
[My son]
[ابني]
Hello, Jun Seo.
مرحبًا جون سيو.
That?
الذي - التي؟
Is it already that late?
هل الوقت متأخر بالفعل؟
Yes.
نعم.
I'm just with some friends.
أنا فقط مع بعض الأصدقاء.
OK. I'll be home soon, don't worry.
نعم. سأعود للمنزل قريباً، لا تقلق.
I'm coming.
أنا قادم.
I said I'm on my way.
قلت أنا في طريقي.
Bye bye.
وداعا وداعا.
You should go home.
يجب عليك العودة إلى المنزل.
Yes.
نعم.
There are no more drinks anyway.
لا يوجد المزيد من المشروبات على أي حال.
and it's too late.
وقد فات الأوان.
Hey, Boom...
مهلا، بوم...
I'm leaving
سأغادر
I hope we can see each other again.
آمل أن نتمكن من رؤية بعضنا البعض مرة أخرى.
Take care of yourself.
اعتنِ بنفسك.
Leave.
يترك.
Do you want to stay the night?
هل تريد البقاء في الليل؟
Weren't you going home?
لم تكن تذهب إلى المنزل؟
I felt like I needed another drink,
شعرت وكأنني بحاجة إلى مشروب آخر،
so I stopped by the store.
لذلك توقفت عند المتجر.
Seriously...
على محمل الجد...
can I stay the night?
هل يمكنني البقاء ليلاً؟
- Don't you have a boyfriend? - Yes, but it's not good for Sol.
- ليس لديك صديق؟ - نعم، ولكن هذا ليس في صالح سول.
He's a graduate loser,
إنه خاسر في الدراسات العليا
so I would try it.
لذلك سأحاول ذلك.
- I want to say it's love, but... - Call the police!
- أريد أن أقول إنه الحب، ولكن... - اتصل بالشرطة!
Do you think I will be in Sol's future?
هل تعتقد أنني سأكون في مستقبل سول؟
I was afraid that people would notice
كنت أخشى أن يلاحظ الناس ذلك
how much I like you.
كم أحبك.
Do you really think that Julia
هل تعتقد حقًا أن جوليا
would I want to see you punish yourself like this?
هل أرغب في رؤيتك تعاقب نفسك بهذه الطريقة؟
You don't have to blame yourself.
ليس عليك أن تلوم نفسك.
I'm tired of worrying for what others think.
لقد تعبت من القلق لما يعتقده الآخرون.
Dad?
أبي؟
What was that?
ماذا كان ذلك؟
Hello.
مرحبا.
Daniel, I want you to meet my girlfriend.
دانيال، أريدك أن تقابل صديقتي.
Are you cooking? That's new.
هل أنت الطبخ؟ هذا جديد.
Why are you so nice to him?
لماذا أنت لطيف جدًا معه؟
She's crazy.
إنها مجنونة.
I'm sorry, Jun Kyung.
أنا آسف، جون كيونغ.
What? Have they already left you?
ماذا؟ هل تركوك بالفعل؟